Oh, yeah, I forgot. Today was the day to watch Tiga on TV.
Take a pose, please.
It's a wide angle.
January 19
Special Production Crew - First Shoot Day
Writer, Director, and
Location Scenery Filming, etc
Hideaki Anno
Scene 48C Asuka's Commute
Soryu Asuka Langley / Yuko Miyamura
Action
Let's retake. Let's do it again.
January 22
Matsumoto city, Nagano prefecture
Koufu city, Yamanashi prefecture
Anno-san, weren't you pretty quiet the first day?
Yeah.
Were you respecting the staff there?
I think so and,
I was interested in how they make the film
because it's not my field and,
I was wondering how Higuchi makes films?
My curiosity was way bigger.
Everyone pretty expected something would happen.
Well it was the first day so I was quiet.
We were expecting you to do something.
Anno-san doesn't go crazy.
I was expecting more like...
I'm sorry for making you disappointed.
So when I received word that you broke down after the shoot,
I was like "Damn, how could I miss that!"
-I see.
When I see the shooting as an observer, it makes me want more cuts.
Ah, cutting?
Right.
Yeah I know. You're right, but...
I understand.
In the case of animation, you have a storyboard at the beginning.
Then you figure out how you can make it closer to that.
That's how we make it.
So I have a specific vision in my mind at the beginning.
If I'm faced with a situation like "now what will you do?"
my thoughts get a mess with a bunch of desires.
This is how I felt when I saw it as an observer.
January 23
Scene 48 Tokyo-2, full view, morning
Scene 48A The profile of the town, morning
No. You're not normal if you call yourself a normal person.
January 25
Because you have a desire to feel that you're normal,
at this point it's clear that you're not normal.
A normal person never insists he's normal.
Either that, or you confess that you're a weirdo
before someone points out, like Nanri-san.
You confess before someone points out.
Then you can get a get-out-of-jail-free card in advance.
It's one of the patterns.
Scene 44 Asuka's room and
Well your hair,
Scene 45 6 sqm studio apartment, in the morning
Your hair should be more usual and messy.
You're defenseless.
You don't care how you look.
Let's start with that.
Action
Baka Touji.
Ah right, I went to a bar after work and then slept with him.
I'm bored of ending up with this.
Touji Suzuhara / Tomokazu Semi
Are you changing the line with every take?
Sorry, I changed it just now.
Let's make a good film.
This light is on.
I'm going to give it my best shot.
I'm Shinnosuke (an anime character).
You're hiding this light?
Yeah, this light...
Let's go for it.
...is annoying.
Go for it.
-Yes.
I'm betting on it.
Let's make a good film.
I'm counting on you.
Can we move on to the test shots?
-Okay.
Scene 46 The bathroom in the morning
Then, how about I act like this?
Yes.
I know...
he faked it.
No. I can't believe he faked it.
I know it's just a half-way measure.
It takes time if you want to do something unique.
But it's still faster than the animation.
Once you start taking pictures, it's faster.
This is why live-action takes only one or two weeks.
It was hard for people to believe that I made an animation in a week. They said it must have been fast and sloppy.
Scene 49A Office
What will you do about this?
I keep wearing this on, right?
Sure. Right.
Rei Ayanami / Megumi Hayashibara
We're going to page 13?
That's right.
I got it.
Oops, I'm not supposed to open it.
Don't open it.
To try montage, can we cut some scenes off?
I think it's possible.
We cut some again.
I think there's no problems.
Huh?
This is a wide converter lens.
Is this?
Yeah.
"Do you want to be one with me?"
You got that right.
Do you need to film seriously?
You don't?
Let's move on to the test shots.
-Okay.
Do you like feeling mellow, Anno san?
Hmm, do I like feeling mellow?
Yeah I think I like it.
Ah, you do.
Yeah.
Well I seldom feel happy.
It's a low probability.
Then you don't seek happiness greedily.
Probably not.
I'm pretty happy most of the time.
I'm jealous of that.
For example, food, clothing, hobbies
or whatever can make me feel happy.
Quite simply, I can say I'm happy.
You know, that's a good thing.
You think so?
I do.
I think it's important.
Thanks.
I'm very jealous that you have something like that.
I don't have any of that.
I take the bad side of everything basically.
Oh, I see.
Do you think you have a bad habit of doing that?
Yes. Well, so as to avoid getting hurt later.
You feel safer.
You got it, I get hurt less deeply.
-I see.
I have to force myself to take the bad side from the beginning.
Otherwise, I tend to expect a good thing automatically.
So my emotions rise or get too excited very easily.
Since I know that, I try to be calm as much as possible.
Good morning.
I see.
But you can't be happy if you aren't open to the opportunity to be happy.
Only if you try to catch the opportunity proactively.
You need to ask.
"Ask, and it shall be given to you."
But there are a lot of people who get their energy from adverse circumstances, so it's hard to say for sure.
I like happiness.
Well, if I was surrounded by happiness, I wouldn't be doing this job.
I see.
(Mumbling lines)
I can't keep them in my brain.
January 26
Scene 48C: Asuka's commute
You know, I see a tight facial expression on her face.
She must feel cold.
Well I don't know, you're feeling like "I can't believe that old hag did this to me! I'm late for work now!"
Well it's about that kind of feeling.
You can tighten your lips or…you know...
Okay, I'll try that.
It's better if you have some facial expression.
Like a sour face.
Exactly. Especially in the second half. Try it in the second half of the cut.
It's getting a bit of a forced rendering.
That's how it goes.
That's just the way it is.
Well, take it easy. You can sing a song.
Excuse me, I need to get through there.
Excuse me, I'm sorry I need to get through there.
I'm sorry for bothering you.
Do you mind if I set the face out of the center?
-Not at all.
What?
-She's playing a trick on you.
Let's take it out.
Oh no, you can't do that.
Why not?
I haven't slept at all.
Well, I'm sleeping like three hours.
I'm kinda sleeping.
That doesn't count as sleep.
Scene 50 Evening
March 14
NGE: Death & Rebirth
Opening Night
Special Effects Team. Filming Continues.
Too many people.
NGE: Death & Rebirth
Screening
So let's bring in the voice actors,
our guests for today
Please give a big round of applause.
Good morning everyone.
-Good morning!
Greeting by voice actors from the stage
I'm Emi Ogata voice acting of Shinji Ikari.
Thank you all for coming to the theater in the early morning despite the rain.
How did you like it?
Around 2 months later
May 8
Actually I don't know, either.
What do you think?
I think it's Evangelion.
What's that?
Anime.
Please go ahead.
May 10
Special Effects Team. Last day of shooting.
July 19
The End of Evangelion
Released
Once again, January 22, Night.
When I saw the finished product, I finally realized that live action is live action after all.
Right.
Oh, it's live action!
I don't get it.
Well, in short, it's a movie film.
It's pretty obvious, but that's my first impression of the film.
I felt it turned out to be a rather ordinary film.
I was feeling down but Higuchi's encouragement yesterday cheered me up a bit.
So now I'm thinking of a new script.